翻译:  福尔摩郑 福尔摩珞  福尔摩D  福尔摩犬
翻译:  福尔摩迈  福尔摩爆  福尔摩潇
翻译:  福尔摩宇  福尔摩黛
时间轴:  福尔摩猹  福尔摩苏  福尔摩lock
后期:  福尔摩T    校对&总监： 福尔摩黛
一键收藏网盘资源生活大爆炸 吸血鬼日记
西部世界 谍网 超女
美剧资源应有尽有
扫码即刻关注
Zimuzu特别推荐
马上关注微信人人美剧（rrmjapp）
你有十秒钟解释清楚这些
You got about ten seconds to reach a point with this
否则这水就要扣你头上了
before this water ends up on your head.
描述一下我刚放在柜子上的图
Describe the image I just put on the cabinet over there.
而我不能动吗
And I'm not allowed to move?
你可以  但是记住
You can, but remember
恩奎斯先生特别说了
Mr. Enriquez specifically stated
他当时带着酒钵走向演奏台
that he was walking the punch bowl to the band shell,
就在他要放下时
about to set it thereupon,
他听到了枪声
at the moment he heard the gunshots.
另外记住  地上没有洒出来的酒
Also remember there was no evidence of spilled sangria--
如果有人像你这样  突然转身
as would happen if someone in your position abruptly turned--
现场就该有洒出来的酒
found at the scene.
恩奎斯不可能看见开枪的人
There's no way Enriquez saw the shooter.
他的证词是假的
His statement's a lie.
觉得他是在替谁打掩护吗
Think he's covering for someone?
如果你说的「谁」是指他自己的话
If by "someone" you mean "himself."
在你调查的过程中  你发现
In the course of your investigation you discovered
被害人是个被通缉的野生动物贩子
that the victim was a wanted wildlife trafficker.
特别是  被通缉的原因是从厄瓜多尔
Wanted, most notably, for smuggling
走私珍稀动物加拉帕戈斯鬣蜥
rare Galápagos iguanas out of Ecuador.
恩奎斯先生来自厄瓜多尔
Mr. Enriquez is from Ecuador.
在这些案发当天的照片中
And in these photographs, from the day of the murder,
我看到他手臂上有多处伤痕
I saw multiple scars on his arms
符合加拉帕戈斯鬣蜥的咬痕
consistent with those of Galápagos iguana bites.
相信我  我知道自己在说什么
Trust me when I say I know of what I speak.
你认为这是生意上的争执
You think this was some kind of business dispute?
我认为鉴于恩奎斯先生的假供词
I think that in light of Mr. Enriquez's false statement
值得再查查他
he's worth a second look.
一个便便的表情
A poop emoji?
我以为那是冰淇凌
Oh, I thought it was ice cream.
那是副局长普罗斯基吧
That's Deputy Chief Prosky, isn't it?
是他
That's him.
他是警监的上司吧
He's the captain's boss, isn't he?
有什么问题吗
Is there a... Problem?
实际上  他是警监的上司的上司
Technically, he's the captain's boss' boss,
也就是我的上司的上司的上司
which means he's my boss' boss' boss,
还意味着我决定不多管闲事
which means I'm gonna mind my own business.
但多谢了  现在我知道你觉得有地方不对
But thanks, now that I know you think something's wrong,
我也会开始担心了  我去把这个倒了
I'm gonna be worrying, too. I'm gonna go spill this out.
你最好在普罗斯基看到前  拿走你的「冰淇凌」
You should take down your "ice cream" before Prosky sees it.
不不不  我不要冷静
No, no, no, no, I'm not calming down!
我们的地方被毁了
Our place is trashed!
伦恩  声音小点  让她说
Len, keep your voice down. Let her talk.
我们会处理所有的事  我保证
We'll take care of everything, I promise.
合同里都写了
It's in your contract.
我说过我们不需要房客
I told you we did not need renters, okay?
我们花钱是找人看家的
We should have paid for a house sitter.
空房乐租为这种情况上了保险
AwayKay carries insurance for just such situations.
我们介绍的客人造成了这些损害
Guests we paired you with did all this damage,
-因此我们会负责全部赔偿  -真的吗
- so we'll cover all the costs. - Oh, really?
看见这地毯没  这是古董
You see this rug? It's an antique.
他们会为它赔我五万美金吗
Are they gonna give me 50 grand for it?
不会  我也是这么想的  我要报警了
No, that's what I thought. Look, I'm calling the cops,
这是肆意破坏他人财产
because this is vandalism.
空房乐租和公司章程冲突  咱们会被开除
AwayKaying is against the co-op charter. They could throw us out.
-你早就知道  -房租每月过万啊  伦恩
- And you knew that? - It was 11 grand a month, Len.
什么东西
Now, what the hell?
这是什么鬼  壁炉棍子  还是什么
What the hell is this, a fireplace poker or something?
他们在这里干了什么
What were they doing in here?
等等  在你把那东西拿出来前
Wait, before you pull that out,
先让我给保险那边照张相
let me get a photo for the insurance.
它还挺牢
That's in there pretty tight.
伦恩  你够了吧
Len, will you stop it?
-墙要碎了  -亲爱的  能帮我拿工具吗
You're gonna break the wall. Now, honey, could you get my tools?
那里面到底有什么啊
What is in there?
你不能把它拔出墙  所以...
You're not getting that out of the wall, so...
伦恩  住手
Len, stop it!
住手  求你了
Stop it, please.
福尔摩斯：演绎法
第五季  第四集
我很确定那些案子都解决了
Pretty sure we solved all those cases.
没错  是解决了
You are right, we did.
所以这往事重温是什么意思
So, why the trip down memory lane?
昨晚我在局里的时候  我发现警监
Last night while I was at the precinct I observed the captain
跟他的上司在关着门开会
in a closed-door meeting with a superior officer.
我看到他们在重新过一些结案的案子
I could see they were reviewing a number of closed cases.
我去档案室查了下被取出的档案
I checked the file room to see which files had been pulled,
看看  是咱们的案子
and voilà-- our cases.
或者说  是不少咱们的案子
Or, rather, a curious number of them.
好吧
Okay.
我很想知道
I'm attempting to determine
他们为什么在看这些档案
why they were looking at these particular files
以及他们在讨论什么
and what they were discussing.
咱们又遇上麻烦了吗  还是内务部
Are we in hot water again? Has Internal Affairs
再一次把它严格的目光投向了我们
turned its Orwellian eye on us once more?
如果真是如此呢
So what if they have?
咱们以前经历过这种事
We've weathered the storm before.
我们最近又没有违反什么规定
It's not like we've broken any rules lately.
-没比以往违规的次数多  -确实如此
- Well, any more than usual. - It's true.
但你难道不想知道我们遇上了什么
But wouldn't you rather know what kind of attack
需要自己抵挡的攻击吗
we have to defend ourselves against?
也可能什么事都没有
It could also be nothing.
怎么可能没事
How could it be nothing?
它们不在档案室
Just because those weren't in the file room
并不意味着它们就是警监他们在看的
doesn't mean that they're the ones that they're looking at.
不管怎么回事  警监会支持我们
And whatever it is, the captain's got our back.
如果这事他觉得咱们该知道
So if it's something he thinks that we need to know,
他会告诉咱们
he'll tell us.
我要做早饭了  你吃什么吗
I'm gonna make some breakfast. Do you want anything?
是马库斯
It's Marcus.
喂
Hello?
好的  我们马上过去
Yes, we'll be right there.
起码我们刚知道了  我们还没被禁用
Well, at least we know we haven't been benched just yet.
做点能带在路上吃的早餐吧  华生
Make it breakfast to go, Watson.
被害人叫罗素·科尔
Victim's name is Russell Cole.
这间公寓是他的  临时工发现的他
He owned this apartment. Super found him.
科尔先生在巴瑞特·怀特公司工作
Mr. Cole worked for Barrett White Capital,
一家投资公司
an investment firm.
他是一位定量分析师  搞数学的
He was a quant-- quantitative analyst. Deep math guy.
他们用复杂的公式分析公司
They use complicated formulas to analyze companies
然后作出投资建议
and then make investment recommendations.
没有闯入痕迹
No sign of forced entry.
但是看起来有过打斗
Looks like there was a struggle, though.
所以没人看到或听到什么
So, no one saw or heard anything.
隔壁的人把房子租给了吵闹的空房租客
Well, the folks next door had some noisy AwayKayers.
他们搬走了
They'd moved on,
但其他邻居不知道
but the other neighbors didn't know that,
所以额外的打砸声被忽略了
so a few extra crashes and bangs were just ignored.
再说所有人都以为科尔出城了
Plus everyone thought Cole was out of town.
他们说已经几周没见过他了
They said they hadn't seen him in weeks.
门口的行李包里都是衣服
Overnight bag by the door is full of clothes.
他肯定是刚回家
He must have just come home.
不管怎样  不会有人计划用壁炉火钩
Anyway, nobody shows up planning to commit a murder
实施谋杀的
with a fireplace poker,
所以我觉得这不是预谋好的
so I'm thinking this wasn't premeditated.
科尔让这个人进了门
Cole let the person in,
也许他们互相认识  出于一些原因
so maybe they knew each other and for whatever reason,
情况失控了
things turned ugly.
你错了
You're incorrect.
关于没有预谋这点
About it not being premeditated.
凶手是带着这个来的
The killer came armed with this.
枪把手有纹理  也许很难提取指纹
It's a textured grip, so it might be hard to get prints,
但值得一试
but it's worth a try.
杂志没有放好
Magazine isn't seated properly.
凶器可能是没能开火
That weapon would have failed to fire.
你怎么知道要看那下面
Well, how'd you know to look under there?
如你所说  没人会计划这样实施谋杀
As you said, no one plans to commit a murder this way,
但犯罪的明确性表示这是计划好的
and yet the specificity of the crime suggests it was planned.
这就提出了另一种可能性
And that raises another possible scenario:
凶手是带着凶器来的
the killer came better armed.
发生打斗之后 他或她被缴械了
A fight ensued, he or she was disarmed
然后拿起火钳完成了谋杀
before grabbing the poker to finish the job.
什么明确性
What specificity?
袭击发生的时间
Timing of the attack.
就在科尔先生回家的时候
Just as Mr. Cole gets home.
再加上看起来唯一失踪的东西
Plus the fact that, by appearances,
就是他的笔记本电脑
the only other thing missing is his laptop.
这个包上都是灰  被太阳晒褪色了
This bag is dusty, bleached by the sun,
除了这个区域
apart from this area here.
这个包有一个可移动电脑套
Now, this bag comes with a removable laptop sleeve.
它就在这里  所以如果电脑不见了
It sits right there. So, if his laptop is missing,
也许是被凶手拿走了
perhaps the killer has it.
我们还没找到它
Well, we haven't found it yet.
警监想让我过去聊几句
Captain wants me to stop by for a word,
就像一个人什么都不想讨论时一样
as one does when one wants to discuss nothing.
科尔是华尔街的分析师
Cole was a Wall Street analyst.
他电脑里可能有很多值得杀人的东西
His laptop could have contained a lot of things worth killing over--
内部信息  金融犯罪的证据
insider information, proof of a financial crime.
你去跟警监谈
Well, you go talk to the captain,
我们去科尔的办公室
we'll go to Cole's office,
看看能不能查出他在做什么
see if we can find out what he was working on.
我的天啊
Oh, my God.
这太可怕了
This is horrible.
你跟科尔先生很熟吗
Were you and Mr. Cole close?
罗素不光是为我工作
Oh, Russell didn't just work for me.
他是我的家人
He was family.
他一毕业就来这里工作了
He started here right out of school.
你能想到任何
Can you think of any reason
会让人想杀他的原因吗
someone might have wanted to kill him?
人们经常会对我们不满
I... I mean, people get angry at us all the time.
威胁我们
Threaten us.
如果我们给一家公司评级很低  数百万就没了
We give a company a poor rating, millions of dollars disappear.
但没有这样的情况
But... nothing like this.
罗素最近的工作有没有可能
Was there anything that Russell was working on in particular
让他受到威胁
that might have aroused threats?
抱歉  你们看起来很肯定他是因工作而死
I'm sorry, you seem pretty sure he was killed because of work.
有理由吗
Is there a reason?
我们觉得他的电脑被人拿走了
We think a laptop was taken from his apartment.
也许凶手就是为了
Could be whatever he had on it
电脑里面的东西
is what the person was after.
其实
Well, the truth is
我完全不知道他在做什么
I have no idea what he was working on.
罗素的专长是科技  医药  信息技术  航空
Russell specialized in tech, medicine, I.T., aerospace,
但关于他目前在做什么  我...
but as to what he was into at any given moment, I...
他是我的疯狂天才
He was my mad genius.
他会独自披荆斩棘
He'd beat the bushes on his own,
寻求其他人看不到的机会
look for opportunities no one else saw.
去隐秘的地方
Go off somewhere private,
深入挖掘一家公司的数据
deep dive into a company's numbers.
我给他很大的权限
I gave him a long leash
因为他总能带回金子
because he always came back with gold.
他前几周是不是去挖掘数据了
Was he on one of these deep dives the last few weeks?
他的邻居说他一直不在家
His neighbors said he hadn't been home.
你知道他去哪了吗
Any idea where he went?
不知道
No clue.
我妻子一定会很伤心
Oh. My wife is gonna be devastated.
那是她吗
Is that her?
劳丽  她在某个慈善活动中赢了毛伊岛之旅
Laurie. She won a trip to Maui in some charity thing.
她带了一个女性朋友去
She took a girlfriend.
我想尽我所能帮忙  你们需要什么
I want to help any way I can. What do you need?
我们想检查一下科尔先生的办公室
Well, we'd like to go through Mr. Cole's office,
看看能不能查出他在做什么
see if can figure out what he's been working on.
我们还想看看他的电子邮件和信件
We'd also like access to his e-mails and correspondence
看看有没有人威胁他
so we could look for any threats.
我亲自带你们过去
I'll walk you over there myself.
进来
Come in.
坐吧
Sit down.
我该担心吗
Should I be concerned?
放松  我觉得你昨晚肯定察觉到了
Relax. I had a hunch you picked up a vibe last night
我不希望你一直乱想
and I didn't want you in your head about it.
你昨晚看到的会面  不是你想的那样
The meeting that you saw-- it wasn't, uh, what you think.
我还没决定好该怎么想  但请继续
Well, I haven't decided what I think, but go on.
你听说过表彰日吗
Did you ever hear of, uh, Medal Day?
纽约警局的年度传统
Annual NYPD tradition.
市长和警长为英勇杰出的警官
The, uh, mayor and the police commissioner give out medals
颁发奖章
to officers for valor, distinguished service.
还有会给因公负伤的警察
Not to mention purple shields
颁发紫盾
for those injured in the line of duty.
他们还会给做出模范工作的小队
They also give out something called a unit citation
颁发一种叫小组嘉奖的东西
to squads that have done exemplary work,
今年他们准备给重案组一个
and this year they're giving one out to Major Case.
典礼过几天举行
The ceremony's in a few days.
这是你们应得的  恭喜
Well, that's well deserved. Congratulations.
我没有告诉你和乔恩
I wasn't gonna say anything to you and Joan
是因为这事还不确定
because it still might not happen,
但平民顾问是包括在奖项里的
but civilian employees are included in the award,
我想把你的名字也放到名单里
and I want your names on the list.
没有钱什么的
It isn't money or anything,
你只是会被写入警局的官方记录
you'd just be part of the department's official record
然后每人获得一个奖状
and you'd each get a certificate.
可以用来装饰墙壁
Something to hang on the wall.
我知道了
I see.
我受到了一些阻力
I have been getting some resistance.
我想应该告诉你
I thought you should know about it.
巴瑞特夫人
Mrs. Barrett.
我无意惊吓您  我是乔恩·华生
I don't mean to startle you. I'm Joan Watson.
我是警方的顾问
I work with the police.
我在调查罗素·科尔谋杀案
I'm investigating the murder of Russell Cole.
是的  我丈夫告诉我了
Yes, my husband told me.
你丈夫办公室有张你在烤猪野宴上的照片
Your husband has a photo in his office of you at a luau.
我注意到镜头一角被什么东西挡住了
I noticed there was something blocking the lens in one corner.
我大概知道那是什么  所以我查了查
I had an idea what it was, so I looked into it.
照片是用罗素的手机拍的
That picture was taken on Russell's phone.
他的手机壳破了
His case was broken,
塑料碎片凸出来挡住了镜头
and a piece of plastic was sticking out over the camera.
警方本以为那是在谋杀过程中被损坏的
Police thought it had been damaged during the murder.
但我记起在他家里看到一张照片
But then I remembered seeing a picture at his place
上面有着同样的异物
with the same obstruction.
所以那手机壳已经破了一段时间了
So the case had been broken for some time.
罗素就是你带去毛伊岛的那个朋友
Russell was the friend you took to Maui.
你们俩有婚外情
You were having an affair.
而鉴于你丈夫还留着旅行的纪念品
And considering your husband has a memento from the trip,
我猜他还不知道
I'm guessing he doesn't know.
对  他不知道
No, he-he doesn't.
我发誓  罗素的事和我没关系
And I swear, I had nothing to do with what happened to Russell.
我非常伤心
I'm a wreck about it.
目前你并不是嫌疑人
Right now you're not a suspect.
但我需要你提供些信息
But I need some information from you
我们正在试图找出
We're trying to find out
罗素最近几周待在了哪里
where Russell had been staying the last few weeks.
警察检查了他的车和他的信用卡
Police checked his car and his credit cards.
他们确定他没有开车出城太远
They're pretty sure that he didn't drive too far outside the city.
你和他去过毛伊岛
Now, you went all the way to Maui with him.
所以我想也许他带你去过他
So I thought maybe he'd taken you to the place
玩"深潜"的地方
where he does his deep dives.
他有一个...
He has a...
小屋  在熊山附近
a cabin near Bear Mountain.
往北部一小时的路程
It's about an hour upstate.
这周围有大量的毒藤
Copious amounts of poison ivy around.
看着点路
Watch your step.
你是怎么比我们先到的
How'd you get here before us?
你应该记得我认识一家直升飞机公司的老板
You'll recall I know the owner of a helicopter company.
有一架要飞向这边
There was one going this way.
我就搭了个顺风机
I hitched a ride.
-你进去过了吗  -没有
- You been inside? - No.
我刚到这里没多久
I just got here a short while ago.
这里吸引我关注的东西挺多的
Plenty to keep me occupied out here.
那么  只有一辆车最近留下了轮胎印
So, only one vehicle has left recent tire tracks.
胎面与罗素·科尔的吻合
The tread matches that of Russell Cole's.
同样的  最近的足迹也是他的
And, likewise, the only recent footprints are his.
所以他的确来过这里  并且他没有访客
So he was here, and he didn't have any visitors.
看来他不想把生意和享乐混在一起
Guess he didn't like mixing business with pleasure.
我是说  除了睡老板的老婆
I mean, besides sleeping with the boss' wife.
我不是专家  但这看起来不是金融资料
I'm no expert, but this doesn't look financial.
更像是科学
More like science.
是关于质量和半径
Stuff about masses and radii
还有反射系数的
and reflection coefficients.
你说得对
You're right.
这些是物理公式
These are physics equations.
其实是天文学
Astronomy, to be exact.
好吧  所以科尔是来这里看星星的
Okay, so Cole was up here stargazing.
这些和华尔街有什么关系
What does any of this have to do with Wall Street?
很难说
That's difficult to say.
但我想我知道他是为什么被杀的了
But I do think I understand what he was killed over.
没什么比地球上生命的未来更重要
Nothing less than the fate of life on Earth.
所以  这些点都是小行星
So, all these dots are asteroids?
它们的近似点  没错
An approximation of them, yes.
当然  不是所有现存的小行星
Not all asteroids in existence, of course.
显然的  它们数以万亿计
Obviously, there are hundreds of millions of those.
这里有五千个左右
These are the 5,000 or so
是航天局定性为有危险性的
that NASA has deemed potentially hazardous,
它们的轨道和地球的轨道相交
those whose orbits intersect with the Earth's
因此有着导致大灾难的可能性
and therefore pose a threat of cataclysmic collision.
同样的碰撞曾灭绝了恐龙
Such a collision wiped out the dinosaurs,
以及同时期大部分其他生物
along with most other life at the time.
这里任何一个点都能导致那样的事件
Any one of these dots could represent the next such event,
也将是人类历史上最后一个事件
which would be the last event in human history.
但那里只有五千个
But there are only 5,000 of them,
还挺让人放心的
so that's reassuring.
重点在于"可能"的大灾难
Emphasis on "potentially" hazardous.
但是坐稳了  因为你肚子里感觉到的
But brace yourself, because that existential knot of terror
那股存在主义恐惧感将会更加强烈
you're feeling in your stomach is about to grow tighter.
一星期前  科尔提了篇论文给个科学博客
A week ago, Cole submitted a paper to a science blog,
说他相信我们看待
saying that he believed the whole way
小行星的方式是错的
we're looking for asteroids is wrong.
「对近地球小行星的错误计算
"Miscalculating Near-Earth Asteroids
以及人类灭亡危机」
and the Threat to Human Existence"?
他写到科学家在过去几年
He wrote that scientists have detected thousands of
发现了上千个新的小行星
new asteroids in the last few years.
但据他说
But according to him,
我们对它们大小的测量完全错误
our measurements of their sizes are useless.
当涉及到保护人类种族
And when it comes to protecting the human race
不被大冲撞毁灭  显然大小很重要
from an extinction-level impact, obviously size matters.
只知道小行星在那是不够的
It's not just enough to know that an asteroid is there.
我们还需要知道哪一个是大个的
We need to know which ones are the big ones.
然后呢  叫布鲁斯·威利斯去炸了吗
So that, what, Bruce Willis can go nuke it?
电影《绝世天劫》的梗
出奇的  没错  我们今天看到了
Surprisingly, yes. We've been reading up
这篇文章  有份请求中的提案
on this stuff today-- there are proposals in the works
想送火箭上小行星
to send rockets to asteroids,
去推动甚至炸掉它们
to nudge them or even blow them up.
那科尔说得对吗
So was Cole right?
测量方法真的不正确吗
Are we measuring them wrong?
不知道
No idea.
我们知道这个在华尔街工作的人
Do we have any idea why a Wall Street guy
为什么要研究这事吗
was studying this stuff in the first place?
-不知道  -那我们现在有什么结论
- We don't. - So where does all this put us?
你们好像都不确定他是因为这事被杀的
Sounds like you're not even sure this is what got him killed,
更不用说具体原因了
let alone why.
论文里的技术细节超出了我的知识范围
The technical minutiae of the paper are beyond my expertise.
我有些看不懂
I'm at something of a loss.
-但是  -有个这方面的专家
- But...? - Well, there's an expert
我有时会向他请教
in the field I consult from time to time.
不过这一般不是我的首选项
But doing so is never really my first choice.
那我帮你做决定  去找他
Well, I'm gonna make it easy for you. Do it.
而且这不光是为了破谋杀案
And not just to solve this murder.
如果世界真要灭亡了
If the world is coming to an end,
我想提前知道
I want to know about it.
纽约科学中心
朱利斯·肯特  宇宙大使
科学家估计我们的宇宙
We scientists estimate that our universe
已经有一百四十亿年了
is 14 billion years old.
想知道我们是怎么估计的吗
Ever wonder how we know?
其实  有很多方法
Actually, in a number of ways.
其中一种方法是测量残余的辐射
One of them is by measuring the radiation that's left over...
朱利斯·肯特  宇宙大使
Julius Kent, Ambassador to the Cosmos.
纽约科学中心
朱利斯·肯特  宇宙大使
-他经常上电视  是个名人  -是的
- He's on TV all the time. He's famous. - Yep.
著名的天文学家  因为很显然
Celebrity astronomer. Because apparently the world
人们需要用通俗的话来理解科学
needs science explained to it with jazz hands.
我们以前是寄宿学校的同学
We were at boarding school together.
他当时和现在一样很能吹
He was every bit the blowhard then that he is now.
十年前  他帮我计算了太阳耀斑的时间
Ten years ago, he helped me time a break-in to coincide
好让我闯入到一个地方
with a solar flare.
无线电干扰可以使探测器探测不到我
The radio interference enabled me to avoid detection.
-干得很漂亮  -那你为什么不愿意找他
- It was good. - So why didn't you want to call him?
因为每次找他帮忙的时候  他都会沾沾自喜
Because every time I ask for his help, he gloats.
你跟格雷森谈得怎么样
Oh, how did that conversation with Gregson go?
-我们又被开除了吗  -恰恰相反
- Are we fired again? - The opposite, of sorts.
重案组要获得嘉奖
The Major Case Squad is receiving a commendation,
他在努力把我们也加入到名单中
and he's lobbying to have us included.
由于官方报告上都没有我们的名字
Thanks to our habit of keeping our names out
即使有也把我们的贡献说得很小
of official reports, or at least minimizing our roles,
所以他很难说服荣誉委员会的人
he's having trouble convincing the honor committee.
无论结果怎样
Well, however it goes down,
他愿意替我们出头就很让人感动
it's nice that he's sticking his neck out for us.
我倒是希望他不这么做
I'd rather he didn't.
你知道我不喜欢这种嘉奖  华生
I eschew such recognition, Watson. You know that.
我跟警监说了  可他不听
I've reminded the captain of such, but he's persisting.
-所以我就用了其他方法  -其他方法
- So I initiated other steps. - Other steps?
你知道还能怎么做吗  你可以说声谢谢就好
You know what you could do? You could just say thank you,
正常人都会这么做
like a normal human being.
夏洛克
Sherlock.
这位一定就是乔恩了
And this must be Joan.
很荣幸见到你  夏洛克从没说过
It's a pleasure. Sherlock never said
你们俩是朋友
that you two knew each other.
是的  我不感到意外
Yes. I'm not surprised.
认识我好像让他很掉价似的
My very existence seems to embarrass him.
要是没有我的话  我们的这位朋友
You know, if it weren't for me, our friend Sherlock
还以为太阳是绕着地球转呢
would still think that the Sun revolves around the Earth.
我犯这个错的时候才八岁
I was eight when I made that mistake.
可你现在竟然还穿这种马甲
You chose to wear that vest this morning.
这是粉丝送的
It was a gift from a fan.
我怎么能拒绝呢
How could I resist?
你有自尊啊
With self-respect.
罗素·科尔和他的小行星警告
So, Russell Cole and his Asteroid Admonition.
夏洛克说你已经看过他的论文了
Sherlock said that you were already aware of his paper?
在我们的圈子了激起了不小的风波
It made quite a splash in my circles.
来吧  我解释给你们听
Come, I'll explain it to you.
当然了  用大白话
In layman's terms, of course.
简单来说
So, in a nutshell,
小行星是由太阳提供热量
asteroids are warmed by the Sun.
用常规方法我们很难观察它们
They're very hard to see by conventional means,
所以我们通过红外线来寻找它们的热量
so instead we look for their heat, using infrared.
理论上来说  我们可以分辨出
And, theoretically, we can tell the difference
大小不同的热物体
between a large warm object and a small one,
也就是小行星的大小
i.e., the size of the asteroid.
目前还能听懂
Makes sense so far.
但是根据罗素·科尔的说法
But according to Russell Cole,
这种方法是无效的  因为没有考虑组成
this fails to take into account what the asteroids
小行星的物质成分  主要是碳
are actually made of. Some are mostly carbon,
还有铁  甚至还含有铂和金
others more iron, many even contain platinum and gold.
也就是说有的小行星外表是暗的
Which means that some asteroids have dull, dark surfaces
而另一些是亮的
and others have light, shiny ones.
我相信就连夏洛克都能
And I'm sure even Sherlock can tell us
说出这会有什么影响
the effect that that would have.
深色的表面会吸收更多的热量
Dark surfaces get hotter than light ones.
所以  如果他是正确的
Which, if Cole is right,
也就意味着我们测量小行星大小的方法全错了
means that we've been seeing asteroid sizes all wrong.
那他正确吗
Was he right?
没人知道
No one knows.
科尔是个优秀的数学家
Cole was a fine mathematician,
但天体物理学不是他的专业
but astrophysics wasn't really his field.
他的论文里有很多错误
His paper was rife with errors
而且有些工作还没完成
and incomplete work.
我们圈子要花几个月的时间才能得出结论
It'll take the community months to reach a consensus.
当然  我会提供帮助
I'll help, of course.
这世界真是多亏了有你
The world will sleep easier.
科尔在论文里说他正在研究一个解决方案
Cole mentioned in his paper that he was working on a solution.
你能想出有什么人想要阻止他吗
Can you think of anyone who would want to stop him?
很容易啊  那些依靠用现有方法
Well, naturally. Anyone whose livelihood depends on
测量小行星大小吃饭的人
the current methods of determining asteroid size.
因为科尔的论文
Because of Cole's paper,
美国宇航局已经搁置了一项提案
NASA's already shelved one proposal.
一个名为皮亚齐的绕轨道运行的红外线望远镜
An orbiting infrared telescope called Piazzi.
而许多小设备会从
And much of the equipment would have been bought
小型私人公司那里采购
from small private companies.
这些公司会失去他们的主要收入来源
Those companies have just lost their prime source of income.
可能跟他们有关系的人很生气  杀了科尔
Maybe someone associated with them killed Cole in anger.
这项目能有多少钱
So how much money are we talking about?
皮亚齐项目的总共预算吗
The total budget for Piazzi?
大约五亿美元
Around $500 million.
你以前真的以为太阳绕着地球转吗
You really thought the Sun revolved around the Earth?
我当时才八岁
I was eight.
是马库斯
It's Marcus.
我们都在这
Hey. We're both here.
刚看到留言说有一通电话
Just got a message about a call that came in.
新城餐馆的一名女服务生在新闻里认出了科尔
A waitress up in New City recognized Cole on the news.
说他在过去的几周
Said he was in her diner a bunch of times
去了她的餐馆几次
over the last few weeks.
从他的小屋过去喝咖啡也太远了吧
That's a long drive from his cabin for coffee, no?
在这里和熊山的中间
It's halfway between here and Bear Mountain.
或许他去见什么人
Maybe he was meeting someone?
也只能这么怀疑了
That's as good a guess as any.
她跟接电话的警探说
All she told the detective who talked to her
她觉得科尔举止很奇怪
was she thought Cole behaved strangely.
我觉得有必要开车去看看
I figure it's worth a drive to check it out.
华生马上跟你一起去
Watson will join you presently.
-只有我吗  -一个可能看到了
- Just me? - A waitress who may
科尔离开小屋去吃饭的女服务员
have seen Cole leave his cabin for meals--
我俩都去可能有点多余
both of us checking that out seems a little excessive.
由于朱利斯  我们现在有了确凿的动机
Thanks to Julius, we now have a concrete theory of motive.
皮亚齐项目流产导致了很多公司亏损百万
A dozen companies lost millions upon the death of Piazzi.
我们中的一个应该留下来调查这些公司
One of us should stay behind and start combing through them.
你可以在车里工作的
You could work in the car, you know.
我在城里还有件事要办
I also have an appointment to keep here in the city.
就是他
That's him.
每两三天就来一次
Came in once every two or three days,
总在午餐和晚餐之间
always right between lunch and dinner.
你有见过他在这里见什么人吗
Did you ever see him meet with anyone while he was here?
他总是一个人吃饭  没跟别人说过话
He always ate alone, didn't talk to anyone.
你打来的时候说有些奇怪的行为
When you called, you mentioned some kind of strange behavior.
能说说是什么意思吗
Can you tell us what you meant?
可能没什么
It might be nothing.
但我看新闻说他被杀了
But I saw he was murdered.
你知道新闻里总说的
And you know what the news always says--
看到任何事都要说
see something, say something.
他总带着电脑  但他在这里从来不用
He always had a laptop with him, but he never used it in here.
他吃完就会拿到停车场里
After he'd eat, he'd take it out there to the parking lot.
在那里用一会电脑
He'd do a little work on it,
就站在那墙边
just standing over there, by the wall,
然后开车离开
and then get in his car and go.
顾客总在这里工作  我们也很支持
Customers work in here all the time. We encourage it.
为什么他要走到外面
Why'd he need to go outside?
可能科尔在找无线信号
Maybe Cole was looking for a Wi-Fi signal.
可能是在黑入某个公司
Could have been hacking into a business,
可能那栋楼里的一家
maybe one inside this building.
我觉得不是
I don't think that's it.
这是U盘吗
Is that a thumb drive?
看上去有人凿了一个洞
Looks like someone drilled a hole
以便他们埋在墙里
so they could bury it in the mortar.
我觉得这是个秘密情报传送点
I think it's a dead drop.
我以前看到过  这样双方就能
I've seen it done like this before. It's so two parties
在网上不留痕迹地交换数据
can exchange data without leaving a trail online.
科尔应该不是来找信号的
I don't think Cole was out here looking for a signal.
他是把电脑插入这里
I think he was plugging his laptop into that
上传下载信息
to get information on and off of it.
我的车里有工具
I think I've got some tools in my car.
感谢你来见我
Thank you for seeing me.
我该称你为「普罗斯基副局长」
Do I address you by the full "Deputy Chief Prosky"?
-还是「普罗斯基局长」  -拜托
- or just "Chief Prosky"? - Come on.
有了汤米·格雷森说的你和你的搭档的那些事迹
After all Tommy Gregson has told me about you and your partner,
你怎么称呼我都行
you can call me anything you want.
我能如何帮你
What can I do for you?
我想跟你谈谈
Um, I'd like to talk to you
关于你跟格雷森警监之间的谈话
about your conversations with Captain Gregson,
还有表彰日的事
and about Medal Day.
-说吧  -首先
- Fire away. - Well, first of all,
我想说我对于警方
I would like to say, that, uh, I have the greatest respect
有着崇高的敬意  而对其服务的表彰
for the men and women in blue, and commendations for service
我也决不会视同儿戏
are not something I take lightly.
无可争议
No argument here.
但是
But, um...
如果你不介意的话  福尔摩斯先生
...if you don't mind, Mr. Holmes, uh,
容我插嘴一句
let me jump in here.
听起来你知道
It sounds like you know that
汤米让我们处境尴尬
Tommy has put us in a tough spot.
在正常情况下
Now, under perfect circumstances,
把你加入「小组嘉奖」是
including you in a Unit Citation would be, uh...
不正规的
Well, unorthodox.
除此之外  你和华生女士
And on top of that, you and Ms. Watson
还有一些争议
have had your share of, uh, controversy,
至少这么说
to say the least.
然而荣誉委员会
The Honor Committee
并不是要拒绝
is not saying no, yet,
只是我们可能没法表彰你们
but we may not be able to square it.
你听到我要说的话应该会如释重负的
I think you'll be relieved by what I have to say.
我希望退出你们的考量范围
Respectfully, I'd like to bow out of consideration.
我试图劝服警监
I tried to persuade the captain
撤销他的请求  但无果
to rescind his request, but, uh, to no avail.
所以我整理了一张细则表
So instead, I, um, I've compiled a list of technicalities,
我觉得警局能加以利用
which, I think, the department could invoke.
其中任何一条
Any one of them
都能逼警监撤回申请
should compel the captain to withdraw,
既能让我不用参与其中
whilst keeping me out of it,
也能让你告诉他你尽力了
and allowing you to tell him that you did your best.
天啊
Uh, boy...
你和你的搭档得商量好你们到底想怎样
You and your partner need to get straight what it is you want.
您什么意思
I beg your pardon?
你的搭档
Your partner.
她来这里的时候对此很积极
She was all for it when she was in here.
-我的搭档  -没错
- My partner. - Yeah.
-她来过这里  -没错
- Was here. - Yeah.
你们在U盘上找到的就是这些了吗
This is everything you found on the thumb drive?
这些消息  还有多份罗素·科尔论文草稿
These messages, plus multiple drafts of Russell Cole's paper.
他不是自己写的  他有个帮手帮他
He didn't write it by himself, he had a partner who helped.
他们逐字逐句商量了所有的细节
They went over every detail together, word by word.
这个帮手的名字呢
This partner have a name?
他们交流的时候不用名字
They didn't use names when they communicated,
也说得通  他们已经用了情报秘密传递点
which makes sense, they were already using a dead drop
来保密他们的合作
to keep their partnership a secret.
我不明白的是
Here's what I don't get.
你跟一个说这篇论文
You talked to someone who said
漏洞百出的人谈过
that that paper was full of sloppy work.
而我们却现在发现有两个人
Now, we find out two people
非常仔细地检查过这文章
went over it with a fine-tooth comb.
问题就在这  由此看来
Well, that's the thing, it looks like
那些错误都是故意写出来的
all these mistakes were deliberate.
他们想让相关领域专家
They wanted it to take months
花费数月时间来解决疑问
for experts in the field to untangle.
这篇文章就是故意写来搞垮皮亚齐观测计划的
The paper was designed to kill the Piazzi telescope project.
就是那个价值五亿美元的计划
The one that's worth half a billion dollars.
科尔的同伙就是背后的煽动者
Cole's partner was the instigator.
他许诺出大价钱让科尔发表文章
He promised to pay Cole big time for publishing the paper.
但你看最后几条信息
But check out the last couple of messages.
两倍太多了  但我明白你的意思了
我们可以再商量  你可以回来了
周一晚七点  你公寓
他要加价
He was upping the price.
科尔想要更多的钱
Cole wanted more money.
他同伙答应可以商量
The partner agreed to talk about it,
并让他回到城里来
and told him to come back into the city.
他们打算两天前夜里在科尔的公寓见面
They were gonna meet at Cole's apartment two nights ago.
就是科尔被杀的那晚
The night Cole was murdered.
我们之前以为科尔的文章伤到了什么人
We've been thinking someone who was hurt
这个人出于愤怒杀死了科尔
by Cole's paper killed him in anger,
但由此来看  他可能
but it turns out, he may have been killed
死在雇他写文章的人手里
by whoever hired him to write it.
你们这儿的人都是这么办事的吗
Is this how you people conduct your business?
居然骗一个全力配合的人
You lie to someone who does nothing but cooperate.
-假借名义把我骗到这里  -我们说的是
- Lure me here under false pretenses. - We told you
我们对案子有疑问  我们现在就在提出疑问
we had some questions about the case, we're asking them.
你可没说我是嫌疑人
You didn't tell me I was a suspect.
我把罗素当成兄弟
I loved Russell like a brother.
我怎么会杀他
Why would I have killed him?
科尔发表文章的目的
The paper Cole published was hand-crafted
是为了搞垮某个宇航局计划
to kill a NASA project.
这会给很多私人企业造成上百万损失
It cost multiple private companies millions.
我们认为这是市场操控
We think it was market manipulation.
你说过  你的数量化投资能搞垮一家公司
You said yourself how your quants can destroy a company,
并且你所处的位置恰好可以跟科尔共谋
and you were in the perfect position to conspire with Cole.
根据我们的研究  被攻击目标可能是
Based on our research, the likely target
一家叫天鹅座光学设备公司的望远镜生产商
was a telescope manufacturer named Cygnus Optics.
他们的估值
Their value's plummeted
由于皮亚齐观测计划的搁置而下滑
as a result of the shelving of the Piazzi project,
从而出现了完美的投资机会
creating an ideal investment opportunity.
所以你就抓住了这个机会
One that you have taken advantage of.
证监会表格
股权收买证书
你知道这家公司的经济基础稳固
Knowing the company to be fundamentally sound,
你也敢肯定它的估值一定会恢复
you'll be confident that its value will recover.
文章发表后
Once the paper was published,
你让科尔低调行事
you told Cole to lie low.
你让他待在自己的小屋里
You wanted him to stay in his cabin,
应该是要找解决方案
supposedly working on a solution,
这样他就不会在危害发生时
so that he would be unavailable
接受别人的采访了
to answer questions while the damage took hold.
可后来科尔变得贪婪了
Then Cole got greedy.
想要更多的分成
Asked for a bigger cut.
你让他回到自己公寓来  你就在那杀了他
Told him to come back to his apartment, where you killed him.
你拿走了他的电脑  这样就不会有人发现
You took his laptop, so no one would find
你们俩之间的通信往来
the messages you'd been trading.
我们觉得你最终也会铲掉
And we figure you would have picked up the thumb drive
新城餐馆墙上的闪存口  可谁知道呢
in New City eventually, but who knows?
它隐藏地那么好
It was well hidden.
你可能觉得不会被人发现
Probably, you just figured no one would find it.
你们说对了一件事
You're right about one thing.
我投资了天鹅座光学设备公司
I invested in Cygnus Optics.
都暴跌成那样了
You would have, too,
换你  你也会投资的
after the nosedive it took.
但我完全不知道罗素写假文章的事
But I didn't know anything about Russell writing a phony paper.
他是周一晚上被杀的吧  几点
He was killed on Monday night, right? What time?
法医推断在七点至九点之间
M.E. puts it between 7:00 and 9:00.
我当时正在吃晚餐
I had a dinner.
商量新公司首轮公开募股的事
We were going over a new IPO.
十几个人都能帮我证明
A dozen witnesses can put me there.
我说我在意罗素
You don't believe me
你们并不相信我
when I say I cared about Russell.
你们觉得我只在乎钱
You think I only care about money.
那好  我们就来聊聊钱
So fine, let's talk about money.
我之前说过  他是我的摇钱树
I told you before, he was my golden goose.
你们看看过去八年的年度报告
Look at my annual reports over the last eight years.
在证监会就能查到
They're all on file with the SEC.
你们就知道他对我来说有多大价值了
Count up how much money he was worth to me over time.
你们说罗素想让同伙给他两倍价钱
You said Russell wanted his partner to pay him double?
我愿意出价十倍  二十倍
I would have given him ten times what he was asking... 20.
完全不是问题
It would have been easy.
你们想逮捕我  好啊
You want to arrest me? Fine.
但你们最后肯定会自取其辱
But you're gonna embarrass yourselves.
你们抓错人了
You've got the wrong guy.
-放走了科尔的老板  -暂时而已
- Cutting Cole's boss loose? - For now.
我们没有一小时前对他那么感兴趣了
We're not liking him as much as we did an hour ago.
他提供了不在场证明  我去核实一下
He gave us an alibi, I'm gonna check it out.
你们现在仍然觉得这事的目的
Are we still thinking this is all about tanking
是为了搞垮一家天文设备公司吗
a telescope company?
天鹅座光学设备公司仍然是最有可能的原因
Cygnus Optics is still our best theory,
但如果米其·巴瑞特与此无关
but if Mitch Barrett didn't have anything to do with it,
我们就要找出其他想要破坏这家公司的人
we have to find out who else had reason to hurt them.
这五亿的损失
One project's $500 million loss
可能会落入别人腰包
could be another's gain.
在调查朱利斯·肯特
Now, whilst researching the information
提供的信息时
that Julius Kent gave us,
我找到了一位
I identified somebody who could speak to
能对所有在审的小行星探索计划
all the asteroid-hunting projects
负责的人...
in consideration...
女议员克莉丝汀·萨拉查
Congresswoman Kristen Salazar,
纽约第31区的
from New York's 31st District.
她是白宫空间和科学基金会的
She sits on the House subcommittee
小组成员
for space and science funding.
我发现她这一周都在她曼哈顿的办公室里
Turns out she's in her Manhattan office all this week.
你想跟她谈谈
You're thinking talk to her,
看是否能找到别的嫌疑人
see if any other suspects jump out.
今天早些时候
When I attempted to contact her
我多次尝试跟她取得联系
several times earlier in the day,
可她却没有回复
my calls went unreturned.
因此我请朱利斯用他的名人效应试试看
So I asked Julius to try and leverage his celebrity,
看能否得到她的注意
see if he could get her attention.
她果然抽空把会面时间安排在了
And she made space in her schedule
明天一早
first thing tomorrow.
抱歉让你们久等了
I'm sorry to keep you waiting.
我刚刚在打电话
I was on a call.
这儿一向乱糟糟的
It's always a madhouse around here.
没关系
Of course.
看来你们已经见过我的科学顾问了  格兰特
I see you've already met my science advisor, Grant,
他在这些方面是专家
which is good because he's the expert on all this.
大家请坐
Everyone, please.
你们应该听说了我们正在调查
I'm sure you heard that we are investigating
-罗素·科尔的谋杀案  -当然
- the murder of Russell Cole? - Of course.
他的文章让我们被迫将皮亚齐束之高阁了
He wrote the paper that forced us to mothball Piazzi.
太不幸了
It's simply tragic.
无论科尔的断言是对是错
And whether his assertions turn out to be right or wrong,
他显然天资过人
clearly Mr. Cole had a singular mind.
你们可能没察觉到
In ways that you may be unaware.
我们有证据证明
We've discovered evidence that
科尔先生是故意暗中破坏皮亚齐的
Mr. Cole undermined Piazzi... intentionally.
所以我们想知道谁能从他的行为中获益
So we'd like to know who profits from his actions.
我不明白
I don't understand.
你是说我们被摆了一道吗
Are you saying we were played?
可以这么说
In so many words.
那笔本应属于皮亚齐项目的五亿资金
The $500 million that would have gone to Piazzi,
会被重新分配给其他项目吗
is it going to be allocated to a different project?
不会  那笔钱哪都不会去
No, no, the money doesn't go anywhere,
不会被重新分配
it just doesn't get allocated.
我觉得你们忽略了大局
But I think you're missing the bigger picture.
那篇文章对所有小行星探索项目都造成了冲击
That paper hurt all asteroid-hunting projects equally.
当然  有些竞争项目
Obviously, there are competing projects
肯定想快人一步
that would have loved to cut ahead,
但这都是基于同一个前提的
but they all rely on the same principles
那就是受到了科尔文章的影响
that Cole's paper attacked.
他们都没有考虑
They all failed to take into account
小行星的成分
what asteroids are made of.
根据他的文章  所有人都在犯同一个错误
According to his paper, everyone is making the same mistake,
因此所有拟定项目都被无限期推迟了
so all proposed projects are on an indefinite hold.
如果你说的是真的
I mean, if what you're saying is true,
罗素·科尔做出的事就是灾难性的
Russell Cole has done something catastrophic.
不管他的动机是什么
Whatever his motives,
他的文章提出了真实合理的问题
his paper raised real, legitimate questions.
我们现在无法重新启动
We can't un-ring that bell now.
得等同业互查结束
We've gotta let the peer review play out.
政府资金也不是那么容易拿到的
And government funding doesn't come easily,
尤其是太空研究
especially not for space research.
即便专家断定他是错的
Even if the experts decide that he was wrong,
要让小行星研究重回正轨也要近十年
it could take a decade to get asteroid research back on track.
在思索宇宙的种种奥秘吗
Contemplating the mysteries of the universe?
只是一种奥秘
Just one, actually.
我对这个案子有了新的理论
I've developed a new theory of the crime,
而且我越来越喜欢这个理论了
which I'm liking more and more.
你身上为什么一股香蕉松饼的味道
Why do you smell like a banana muffin?
燕麦粥糊
Oh, its a paste of oatmeal,
小苏打  香蕉皮还有黄莲根
baking soda, banana peel, and goldenseal root.
自制止痒药
It's a homemade anti-itch remedy.
我好像起疹子了
I seem to be developing a rash.
你在科尔的小屋那边
Well, you must have touched some poison ivy
肯定碰到了什么有毒的常春藤
when you were up at Cole's cabin.
肯定没有
I most certainly did not.
我们到那儿之前你在小屋外面查看来着
You were walking around outside before we arrived.
我应该是你见过的最顶尖的
I'm the foremost expert on poisonous plants
有毒植物专家
you'll likely ever meet.
我没有碰毒藤
I did not touch poison ivy.
燕麦粥作何解释
Proof is in the oatmeal.
那你的理论是什么
So what's your theory?
离开萨拉查议员女士的办公室后
Since leaving Congresswoman Salazar's office,
我一直在想她和胡贝尔先生告诉我们的事
I've been thinking about what she and Mr. Huber told us.
科尔发表的文章
That the effect of Cole's paper
能够将寻找小行星的研究
was to delay the hunt for asteroids
推迟十年
for as much as a decade.
我开始考虑会不会目的就在于此
I started wondering if that was the point.
所以你觉得有人想让我们
So you think someone wants us all to be killed
都被一块大石头杀死吗
by a giant rock?
我的理论不止于此
My theory is much more out there,
可以这么说
so to speak.
洗耳恭听
I'm all ears.
如果对寻找小行星有害的事
What if what was bad for asteroid hunting
对开采小行星有益呢
was good for asteroid mining?
什么
Excuse me?
这些石头上有金子  华生
There's gold in them there rocks, Watson.
还有铂金  很多  正如朱利斯所说
Platinum, too. Lots of it. Just as Julius said.
是的  但在大概2020年之前
Yeah, but nobody's gonna be able to fly a ship
没人能把飞船开上小行星
to an asteroid until sometime in the 2020s.
这是我理论的关键部分  过来
A crucial element to my theory. Come on.
迈克尔·海恩斯  金航执行总裁
"Michael Hines, CEO Aurum Aeronautics.
芭芭拉·托雷西  外部动力执行总裁
Barbara Torrissi, CEO Exterral Dynamics."
大家被科尔文章影响的程度不是一样的吗
I thought everyone was hurt equally by Cole's paper.
我不那么认为了
I no longer think that's true.
这四家公司加起来
Combined, those four companies
投资了数十亿资金
are investing billions towards
在小行星采矿勘察的长期研究上
the long-term prospects for asteroid mining.
各国政府也在注资
The world's governments are also investing
研究小行星
in missions to asteroids,
这大大降低了这些公司的资金压力
which greatly reduces the cost to those companies.
然而政府
Governments, however--
他们只是出于害怕小行星撞击地球
they're driven only by their fear of asteroid impact.
例如美国宇航局  只关心拯救人类
NASA, for example, cares only about saving the human race,
而不是开发稀有金属
not about mining for rare metals.
事实上  我们目前
And the truth is the chances that anything really bad
被撞击的可能性非常小
is going to hit us anytime soon is infinitesimal.
上次灭绝级的撞击是在660万年前
The last extinction-level impact was 66 million years ago.
即便是地区性的毁灭
Even an event that would be locally devastating--
比如一座城市
the loss of a city, for example--
也是5000年一遇
that only comes along every 5,000 years.
相比之下  十年毫无意义
Decade here or there, meaningless.
所以你认为专家们标记小行星的速度太快了
So you think experts are mapping out asteroids too quickly.
一旦他们完成
If they finish,
政府发现在可预见的未来里地球都是安全的
and it turns out the world is safe for the foreseeable future,
就会中断他们的资金
the governments will cut off the funding.
这就给了这些执行总裁们
Which gets one or more of these CEO's
推迟研究的动机
motive to slow things down.
科尔的文章营造了不确定的气氛
Cole's paper creates a fog of uncertainty,
延长了人类对未知事物的恐惧
humanity's fear of the unknown is prolonged,
而他们得以搭乘恐惧的火箭
and they get to ride that rocket of terror
前往他们天空中的金矿
to their gold mine in the sky.
你说的没错
You're right.
那是在外太空  但确实说得通
It's out there. But it makes sense.
只要这些人不介意赌一把运气
As long as whoever it is doesn't mind rolling the dice.
如果我们在未来几年都被小行星从地球上抹去
If we're all wiped out by an asteroid in the next few years,
他们肯定会觉得相当可笑
they're gonna feel pretty silly.
我很确定他们确信这几率对他们有利
I'm certain that they're certain the odds are in their favor.
说到被蒙蔽
Oh, speaking of being blindsided,
我昨天和普罗斯基副局长见了个面
I had a meeting with Deputy Chief Prosky yesterday.
你已经知道这个小组嘉奖的事好几周了
You've known about the unit citation for weeks--
你怎么完全没提过
why didn't you say anything?
因为我知道你一定会反对
Well, because I knew you'd be against it.
所以你知道我会反对
So you knew I'd object...
但你还是密谋接受了荣誉委员会的询问
yet you conspired with the Honor Committee's inquiry nonetheless.
这就是我不跟你说的原因
And this is why I did not bring it up.
我想给你看点东西
I want to show you something.
我并没有密谋
I didn't conspire.
大约一周前荣誉委员会打电话过来
The Honor Committee called about a week ago.
你当时不在家  我去了普罗斯基的办公室
You weren't here. I went to Prosky's office,
回答了一些问题  就这样而已
answered some questions. That's it.
这是什么
What's this?
这是你的戒毒一年徽章
It's your one-year sobriety chip.
没错  那这个呢
Yeah, and what's this?
也是我的戒毒一年徽章
Also my one-year sobriety chip.
一个是我第一年的徽章
One is my first one-year chip,
另一个是我第二年的徽章
the other is my second one-year chip.
-所以呢  -它们没有任何区别
- So? - So they're indistinguishable.
这些奖项  这些绶带  这些饰品
These awards, these ribbons, trinkets,
它们只是象征而已  无关紧要
they're-they're just symbols; they don't matter.
没什么重要的
Not really.
我们所做的工作
The work we do does.
这些工作才是真正重要的
The work is all that matters.
如果这些象征对你来说意义如此之小
If symbols matter so little to you,
你为什么非要反对接受一份证书呢
why are you so against accepting a certificate?
格雷森警监想为我们做点什么
Captain Gregson wants to do something nice for us.
他同时也是我们的朋友
He's also our friend.
我很感激
I appreciate it.
我想让他这么做  这有什么不好呢
I'd like to let him. So where's the harm?
这就好比伸进帐篷里的骆驼鼻子  华生
It's the camel's nose in the tent, Watson.
-什么  -就是得寸进尺
- What? - It's a slippery slope.
我在苏格兰场的时候经历过
I saw it during my time at Scotland Yard.
我拒绝接受任何警方官方嘉奖的原因
The reason I refused to accept any official police credit
就是我一旦允许其发生了
is that once I allow it,
这事就没有个头了
there's no official line as to where it stops.
接着不久我就会开始让整个警局黯然失色
And then soon I begin to eclipse the whole department.
而由此引发的愤懑及其对合作关系
And-and resentment and its inevitable harm
所带来的不可避免的伤害很快就接踵而至
to working relationships quickly follows.
所以你不想接受任何嘉奖
So you don't want to accept any credit
是因为实际上你值得太多赞誉
because the truth is you deserve too much credit.
我们所做的工作太重要了不能被任何因素危及
The work we do is too important to jeopardize.
我放弃了  我去睡觉了
I give up. I'm going to bed.
我想你这不是给我带的枕边早餐
I assume that's not you bringing me breakfast in bed.
我本以为你或许需要一些补偿  我错了
I thought you might need some of my remedy-- I was wrong.
所以我睡觉的时候你给我做了毒藤检测吗
So you checked me for poison ivy in my sleep?
还真是一点都不变态呢
That is not creepy.
我并不需要看除你胳膊以外的其他部位
I had no need to look anywhere other than your arms.
你看起来未接触到毒素
You appear to have been unexposed.
我自己身上的皮疹则扩散了
My own rash, however, has spread.
你仍然确定你没碰到任何毒藤吗
You still sure you didn't touch any?
我确定
I am.
那你怎么会起皮疹的
Then how could you have a rash?
你昨晚睡了之后我继续进行了调查
I continued working after you went to bed last night,
仔细查看了四家小行星采矿公司的资料
poring over information on the four asteroid mining companies.
我相信我不仅确定了一位嫌疑人
I believe I've not only identified a suspect,
而且同时找到了我起皮疹的原因
but also the explanation for my rash.
我坚持认为我没有接触过毒常青藤
I maintain I did not come into contact with poison ivy--
但你和我已经见过杀害罗素·科尔的凶手了
but you and I have come into contact with Russell Cole's killer.
马库斯刚打电话来了
Marcus just called.
警方已经获准进行搜查
The police got permission to go ahead.
所以我们也该快点出发了
So we should head out soon.
我还收到了副局长办公室的消息
I also heard from the deputy chief's office.
他们把我们加入表彰日名单了
They're including us in Medal Day.
警监将代表整个小队参加典礼
The captain is gonna go on behalf of the squad,
然后他会把荣誉证书带回局里
and then he's gonna bring back the certificates
进行分发
to hand out at the station.
你会怎么做  华生
What would you do, Watson,
如果你知道世界末日即将在  比如说
if you knew the world was ending in, say,
一个月内来临
one month's time?
说来听听
Indulge me.
假设一颗直径32公里的小行星
An asteroid 20 miles wide
在我们说话这会正朝我们飞来
is hurtling towards us as we speak.
你昨晚已经表明了你的观点  好吗
You made your point last night, okay?
我们会一直工作到最后一刻
We would both continue doing our jobs to the very end.
我们做的工作很重要
The work we do is important.
我觉得我本该更好地解释
I think I could have done a better job
这为什么很重要
explaining why it's important.
至少向我自己解释这为什么很重要
At least explaining why it's important... to me.
我俩当初刚开始合作的时候
When you and I first started...
我很快就发现了你的优点
I quickly recognized your merits,
不仅是作为一位天生的侦探
both as a detective in your own right...
还有你对我工作过程的助益
and in that you facilitated my own process.
我因你的存在而得以更好地工作
I'm better at the work I do because of you.
但这么多年来
But over the years...
这两点价值相对的重要性翻转了
the relative importance of those two values has flipped.
我现在首要珍视的是我们所做的工作
I now value the work that we do, first and foremost,
因为这些工作是我们一起完成的
because I do it with you.
所以如果有时候我过于保护
So if at times I seem overprotective
我们所建立的这个合作体系
of the system that we've built,
如果我担心其他人的愤懑可能会对其产生影响
if I worry that the resentments of others might disrupt it...
我是有充分理由的
I have good reason.
你昨天晚上给我看的那些徽章
Those chips you showed me last night...
你并不是为了你自己而接受的
you don't accept them for yourself.
你接受它们是因为你是一个团体中的一员
You accept them because you're part of a group.
你接受它们是因为
You accept them because...
你在互助会上所做的一切鼓舞了其他人
the work you did to stand up at a meeting inspires others.
这远比你个人重要
It's bigger than you.
或者我们
Or us.
所以你在颁奖现场出现了
So you show up.
我去准备一下
I'm gonna go get ready.
有人在吗
Hello?
胡贝尔先生
Mr. Huber.
谢谢你过来
Thank you for coming.
福尔摩斯先生  华生女士
Mr. Holmes, Miss Watson.
我接到了朱利斯·肯特的电话
I got a call from Julius Kent.
你们也是来这里见他的吗
Are you meeting him here, too?
是我们让朱利斯邀请你来的
We asked Julius to invite you here.
我们已经见识了他的影响力
We'd seen how much influence he has,
所以我们知道你一定会来
so we knew you'd come.
这样警方就能去搜查你的办公室了
It's so police could search your office,
当然  是议员女士萨拉查批准的
with Congresswoman Salazar's permission, of course.
警察为什么要搜查我的办公室
Why do the police want to search my office?
怎么不直接跟我说  我会同意的
Why not just ask? I'd have let them.
你很自信  觉得没什么可怕的
You're confident you have nothing to fear because you think
因为你觉得没有证据能证明杀了你罗素·科尔
there's no evidence there of you having murdered Russell Cole.
你错了
You are wrong.
你们觉得我杀了罗素·科尔
You think I killed Russell Cole?
是的
We do.
就在你们一起写了那篇文章后
After the two of you wrote that paper together.
简直胡扯
That makes no sense.
我有什么理由
What possible reason would I have
要破坏我帮忙一起赚来的资金
to sabotage the funding I helped get?
你说的是探索小行星的资金
You're referring to the funding for asteroid hunting.
然而  我们把注意力
As it happens, we've shifted our focus
更多地转向了开采小行星
more towards asteroid mining.
在调查涉事公司的时候
While looking into the companies involved in that,
一个熟悉的名字一直跳出来
a familiar name kept recurring.
在你跟着萨拉查女士开始现在这份工作前
Prior to your current job with Ms. Salazar,
你是个与那些公司有着深厚联系的说客
you were a lobbyist with deep ties to those companies.
我们相信就是在那时候
We believe it was in that capacity
你第一次见到了科尔先生
that you first met Mr. Cole.
他对你的一名客户做了分析
He conducted an analysis of one of your clients.
他的日程表显示你们曾多次
His calendar showed a number of dinner dates
共进晚餐
between the two of you.
你还帮忙通过了立法
You also helped get legislation passed
让那些公司有权去开采小行星
giving those companies the right to mine asteroids.
据你的社交媒体照片显示
And based on your social media photos,
你为一名公务员花了大把的钱
you spend way too much money for a public servant.
这表明你的前雇主在花钱让你
Which indicates that your former employers are paying you
确保政府决策会按照他的意思来
to make sure that government decisions go their way.
而最近  要确保如此就包括了
And most recently, that included you
得杀死罗素·科尔
killing Russell Cole.
你们都疯了
You people are crazy.
你们有哪怕一丝证据能证明这些吗
Do you have even a shred of proof to support any of this?
所以才有了现在正在进行的对你办公室的搜查
That brings us to the search currently underway at your office.
犯罪后的某个时间
At some point after the crime,
你把罗素·科尔的笔记本电脑带了过去
you brought Russell Cole's laptop there.
外壳上沾了漆酚
The case was covered in urushiol.
是来自有毒的常春藤叶中的一种油
It's the oil which comes from poison ivy leaves.
你绝对想不到那种油从一个地方
You'd be surprised at how easily that oil transfers
沾到另一个地方有多容易
from one surface to another.
比如  你把电脑放在了你的沙发上
For example, you put the case on your couch.
我坐了沙发  我的皮肤就有了中毒反应
I sat there, and my skin reacted to the toxins.
我不知道你在说什么
I... I don't know what you're talking about.
我没有有毒的常春藤
I don't have poison ivy.
假设是真的
Assuming that's true,
有可能你属于那20%
it is possible that you are in the 20% of people
对它不敏感的人群
who are not sensitive to it.
不管怎样  警方正把你的沙发送去实验室
Either way, police are taking your couch to the lab
采集油渍样本
to collect oil samples.
他们还会拿着你的照片
They're also showing your photograph
去新城的一家餐厅找目击证人
around a diner in New City.
我觉得你被认出来只是时间问题
I think it's only a matter of time before you're recognized.
如果你想合作
If you want to cooperate,
并说出雇你去勾结科尔的人的名字
and share the names of the people who hired you
现在就是你的机会
to conspire with Cole, now is your chance.
以防你不知道
In case you're wondering,
漆酚里会有DNA
urushiol contains DNA.
所以要确认你沙发上的油
So a definitive match between the oil on your couch
和科尔的小屋那边的植物绝对吻合
and the plants at Cole's cabin
是完全可行的
will be attainable.
应该说是有可能
I should say, might be.
我不知道概率有多大  不过
I'm not sure of the odds, but...
我觉得会比小行星出现
I think they're better than an asteroid showing up
将你拉出困局的可能性大
to put you out of your misery.
我当警察三十多年了
I've been a cop more than 30 years now.
我目睹过这个城市的起起落落
I've seen this city go through its share of ups and down.
犯罪率起起伏伏
Crime rates rise and fall.
人际关系时好时坏
People get along or they don't.
近来  你看新闻的时候就会觉得
These days, you watch the news and it can feel like
一切都在分崩离析
everything's falling apart.
我说的不只是这里
And I don't mean just here.
到处都在发生不好的事
Bad stuff happening all over--
时常有警察被杀
cops getting killed.
有时候早上起床都会是种挣扎
Makes it tough some mornings to want to get out of bed.
然而坏人却没有休息的时候
Not that the bad guys will ever take a day off.
我说这些不是想让大家觉得丧气
Now I don't say all this to bring everybody down,
我说这些是想让你们知道
I say all this because I want you to know
是什么让我早上有起床的动力
what gets me out of bed in the morning.
是什么让我每天回来这里
What gets me back here, at work,
做我的工作
doing the job, every day.
是你们
You guys do.
你们所有人
All of you.
这个小队的成员都是人中龙凤
This squad is the finest group of men and women
我无比有幸才能跟你们共事
I've ever had the honor to serve with.
这不只是恭维
And that's not just a line.
而是我们的破案率显示的结果
It's what our clearance rate says.
所以你们今天能受到认可
That's why it was important for me
对我来说非常重要
that you all got recognized today.
因为你们所做的无与伦比的工作
Because the extraordinary work you do,
日复一日
day in, day out, it...
让我钦佩
it amazes me.
这个团队  这个大家庭
This team, this family--
你们是我前进的动力
you guys are what keep me going.
所以  帮我个忙好吗
So, do me a favor, would you?
给你们自己鼓掌喝彩吧
Give yourselves a hand?